A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Educational Interests, Series G FA316
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Colleges
  - Colleges - Brown University - Lincolniana - Miss Hamilton's Portrait, 1931 (Box 53, Folder 371)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $4,000 towards purchase of Baumgras painting.
  - Colleges - Brown University - Lincolniana - Photostating, 1932-1935 (Box 53, Folder 372)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $500 in 1934 and 1935 toward photostating of Lincoln material in other collections for Brown collection. In 1937 he gave $1,000 as a final gift for this purpose. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. B. Van Hoesen.
  - Colleges - Brown University - Lincolniana - Photostating - Pledge, 1937, 1937-1942 (Box 53, Folder 373)
  - Colleges - Brown University - Lincolniana - 1957 Gift of Papers, 1957-1959 (Box 53, Folder 374)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchases 44 documents of Lincoln-Chase correspondence as gift to Brown collection. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David A. Jonah.
  - Colleges - Brown University - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), 1909-1913 (Box 53, Folder 375)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. served on board of Graduate Advisory Committee. Made small, irregular contributions. Much discussion of Y General Secretaries at Brown. Coordination of Y and Brown Union activities. Willard S. Richardson took over John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s direct interest in Y. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made small contributions to budget. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. H. Faunce, Willard S. Richardson, G. Colby.
  - Colleges - Brown University - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), 1920-1928 (Box 53, Folder 376)
  - Colleges - Brown University - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), 1914-1919 (Box 54, Folder 377)
  - Colleges - Brown University - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), 1903-1909 (Box 54, Folder 0377A)
  - Colleges - Bryn Mawr College
    John D. Rockefeller gave $250,000 conditionally for building of power house and dormitory. Additional pledges up to $375,000; $80,000 for rising costs of construction. Laurance S. Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller gifts in 1920s; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and David Rockefeller gifts as tribute to Rufus Jones, 1948. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Miss W. C. Thomas, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller.
    - 1901-1902 (Box 54, Folder 378)
    - 1903-1905 (Box 54, Folder 0378A)
    - 1910-1917 (Box 54, Folder 379)
    - 1935-1955 (Box 54, Folder 0379A)
    - 1948-1962 (Box 54, Folder 380)
    - 1948-1957 (Box 54, Folder 380A)
  - Colleges - Bryn Mawr College - Pledge, June 2, 1920, 1920-1926 (Box 54, Folder 381)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $100,000 for Industrial Relations Department.
  - Colleges - Bryn Mawr College - Carola Woerishoffer Graduate Department, 1923-1926 (Box 54, Folder 0381A)
    Request for endowment declined.
  - Colleges - Bryn Mawr College - Summer School, 1921-1935 (Box 54, Folder 382)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. annual gifts for women worker education.
  - Colleges - Bryn Mawr College - Art Department Professorship, 1959-1961 (Box 54, Folder 383)
  - Colleges - Bucknell College, 1892-1949 (Box 54, Folder 384)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift to Bucknell through American Baptist Education Society. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates.
  - Colleges - Colgate University, 1923-1961 (Box 54, Folder 385)
    Rockefeller contribution to Student Union as tribute to J. C. Colgate. Offers of honorary degrees to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Nelson A. Rockefeller declined. Requests for advice and assistance from presidents of Colgate. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $25,000 as tribute to Charles Evans Hughes, 1954. Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Colleges - Colgate University, 1950-1961 (Box 54, Folder 385A)
  - Colleges - Colgate University - Harry Emerson Fosdick Chair, 1959-1961 (Box 54, Folder 386)
    Contributions by David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - Colgate University - Harry Emerson Fosdick Chair, 1959-1961 (Box 54, Folder 386A)
  - Colleges - Colgate-Rochester Divinity School, 1928-1932 (Box 55, Folder 387)
    Union of two Baptist seminaries. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $1,250,000 to assist consolidated school in Rochester; negotiations on pledge. Later requests for additional funds declined. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift made on premise of easing denominational barriers among faculty and students. Invitations to serve on Board declined by John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Clarence Barbour.
  - Colleges - Colgate-Rochester Divinity School, 1933-1954 (Box 55, Folder 0387A)
  - Colleges - Colgate-Rochester Divinity School, 1949-1961 (Box 55, Folder 0387B)
  - Colleges - Rochester Theological Seminary, 1890-1902 (Box 55, Folder 388)
    John D. Rockefeller's annual and special gifts to Seminary; Frederick T. Gates comments on German language ministry. Seminary united with Colgate Seminary. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Clarence Barbour.
  - Colleges - Rochester Theological Seminary, 1902-1904 (Box 55, Folder 389)
  - Colleges - Rochester Theological Seminary, 1905-1912 (Box 55, Folder 390)
  - Colleges - California Institute of Technology, 1938-1961 (Box 55, Folder 391)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributes toward expenses of Industrial Relations Section. David Rockefeller gift in 1960 for African studies. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - California Institute of Technology, 1959-1961 (Box 55, Folder 392)
  - Colleges - College of Puget Sound, 1934-1948 (Box 55, Folder 393)
    Appeals for aid declined. General Education Board grant. Correspondents include E. H. Todd, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Colby College, 1936-1959 (Box 55, Folder 394)
    All requests for aid declined.
  - Colleges - Colby College, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 0394A)
  - Colleges - College of the City of New York, 1944-1954 (Box 55, Folder 395)
    Declinations of appeals and invitations. Family accepts John H. Finley Award given by CCNY Associate Alumni. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - College of the City of New York, 1947-1959 (Box 55, Folder 0395A)
  - Colleges - College of the City of New York - Finley Award, 1948-1949, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 0395B)
    Award for civic service; John D. Rockefeller 3rd acceptance address.
  - Colleges - College of the City of New York - Finley Award, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 0395C)
  - Colleges - College of William and Mary
    W. A. R. Goodwin appeals for aid in 1924 declined; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift, 1927; aid in restoring Christopher Wren building; other small gifts. Relations between college and Colonial Williamsburg. Personal relations between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and college presidents. Winthrop Rockefeller spoke at 1961 commencement. Correspondents include W. A. R. Goodwin, J. S. Bryan, John E. Pomfrit, Winthrop Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    - undated (Box 56, Folder 396)
    - 1922-1935 (Box 56, Folder 397)
    - 1936-1939 (Box 56, Folder 0397A)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 56, Folder 398)
    - 1945-1948 (Box 56, Folder 0398A)
    - 1951-1961 (Box 56, Folder 399)
  - Colleges - College of William and Mary - Friends of William and Mary, 1940-1954 (Box 56, Folder 0399A)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd annual gift of $100 to college, until 1954 when he became a life member with $1,000 gift.
  - Colleges - College of William and Mary - Endowment, 1932-1939 (Box 56, Folder 400)
    Proposal to make college a privately endowed school; J. S. Bryan elected president in 1934 to engineer shift from state control to private endowment. Discussion of relations between college and Rockefeller, Inc.: would the college take over the restoration or the restoration take over the college? Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Harry F. Byrd, John S. Bryan, Kenneth Chorley.
  - Colleges - College of William and Mary - Institute of Early American History, 1943-1958 (Box 56, Folder 0400A)
    Institute to do research in colonial history. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. underwrites part of first director's salary; changes in directors. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Carl Bridenbaugh.
  - Colleges - Columbia University
    John D. Rockefeller contributes $1,000 toward commercial course, and toward interest payments, 1901-1902. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1919 contribution toward War Deficit; aid to needy student. Laurance S. Rockefeller attends ceremonies for installation of Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1948. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s recommendation of J. Campbell for Treasurer. David Rockefeller and Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller sponsors for Theater Benefit, 1950. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declines honorary degree, 1953, and award for public health service. David Rockefeller declines trusteeship 1953; David Rockefeller on sponsoring committee for 1956 Mozart Festival. Relation of Columbia Arts Project to Lincoln Center. Declinations of various appeals for contributions to the many "little offspring of Columbia." 1954 "Columbia Heritage" article on Rockefeller and Harkness philanthropy re Columbia. Correspondents include M. W. Butler, Seth Low, Mr. and Mrs. Eisenhower, Grayson Kirk, Davidson Taylor, Harry Carman, Raymond B. Fosdick, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    - 1899-1931 (Box 57, Folder 401)
    - 1932-1949 (Box 57, Folder 0401A)
    - 1950-1955 (Box 57, Folder 402)
    - 1956-1961 (Box 57, Folder 403)
    - 1940, 1949-1961 (Box 57, Folder 403A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Article on Stewart Proxy Fight, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 404)
    Proposed monograph discussed by Allan Nevins and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Nothing done about it.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1902-1961 (Box 57, Folder 0404A)
    John D. Rockefeller declines 1902 and 1905 appeals for aid; John D. Rockefeller 3rd $25,000 gift, 1951. Contribution by Abby Rockefeller Mauz.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Contributions, 1949-1961 (Box 57, Folder 405)
    Special contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller towards specific programs.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Contributions, 1949-1961 (Box 57, Folder 0405A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Chair of Psychology, 1899 (Box 57, Folder 0405B)
    John D. Rockefeller give $100,000 to endow chair. Charles Strong, his son-in-law, appointed to chair.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Earl Hall, 1946-1957 (Box 57, Folder 406)
    Appeals for aid declined.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Earl Hall, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 0406A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Honorary Degree, 1959 (Box 57, Folder 0406B)
    Doctors of Laws, honoris causa. Citation.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Alexander Hendry, 1932-1939 (Box 57, Folder 407)
    Anonymous aid for cost of schooling at Columbia.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - School of Engineering, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 408)
    Invitations to serve on committee declined.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - School of Engineering, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 0408A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Science Remaking the World, 1922-1952 (Box 57, Folder 0408B)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. underwrote costs of science publication; was repaid.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - American Assembly, 1950-1961 (Box 58, Folder 409)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. attended organizing luncheon at request of D. Eisenhower. David Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributed to expenses. John D. Rockefeller 3rd attended first conference. Later requests for contributions declined. Correspondents include D. D. Eisenhower, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - American Assembly, 1950-1961 (Box 58, Folder 0409A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - American Assembly - Dr. Wriston's Book, 1957 (Box 58, Folder 0409B)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. so impressed on reading "Diplomacy in a Democracy" that he paid for widespread distribution among government officials.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Barnard College, 1896-1902 (Box 58, Folder 410)
    John D. Rockefeller conditional gift of $25,000 in 1896; $10,000 in 1898. $250,000 endowment pledge, 1901. John D. Rockefeller a member of first board of trustees, 1889. Requests for special contributions usually declined. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution to International Fellowship Program; his concern with architecture of additions to Barnard. John D. Rockefeller 3rd anonymous contribution, 1949. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $1,000,000 in 1950. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, George Rogers, Miss V. C. Gildersleave.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Barnard College, 1936-1949 (Box 58, Folder 411)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Barnard College, 1950-1961 (Box 58, Folder 412)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Barnard College, 1950-1961 (Box 58, Folder 0412A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Barnard College - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1950 Gift, 1949-1958 (Box 58, Folder 413)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $1,000,000 to development funds; securities increase in market value.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Barnard College - Offer for Property, April 7, 1954, 1954-1957 (Box 58, Folder 0413A)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased property between 119th and 120th streets for Interfaith Center; gave Barnard an additional contribution.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Bicentennial, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 414)
    Declinations for various dinners, concerts, conferences, etc. Correspondents include Grayson Kirk, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Bicentennial, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 0414A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Bicentennial - Contributions, 1953-1954 (Box 58, Folder 0414B)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $10,000.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Columbia Associates, 1948-1959 (Box 59, Folder 415)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a charter member until 1958. Dues were $1,000 annually; declination of invitations to dinners and luncheons. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., D. D. Eisenhower, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute, 1951-1957 (Box 59, Folder 416)
    Institute, backed by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, establishes exchange program of Japanese and American intellectuals. Correspondence re program, minutes of committee meetings, lists of intellectuals considered for export. Reports on Fusae Ichikawa's and Dr. Yoshishage Abe's trips to United States; reports by Charles Cole, Fathers D'Arcy and Ford, Harry Carman, and Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt on their trips to Japan. Report on Pilot Project for Japanese-American Cultural Relations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Eleanor Roosevelt, Charles Cole, Sir George Sanson, Harry J. Carman, Saxton E. Bradford, Shigeharu Matsumoto, Yasaka Takagi, D. H. McLean.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute, 1952-1953 (Box 59, Folder 0416A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute - 1953 Study, 1953-1954 (Box 59, Folder 417)
    By Overton, Carman, and Borton on Japanese-American cultural relations.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute - 1953 Study (Box 59, Folder 0417A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute - 1953 Study, 1954-1958 (Box 59, Folder 0417B)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute - Contributions, 1951-1954 (Box 59, Folder 418)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd gifts, in 1951, 1952, 1954, totaling approximately $220,000 for exchange program.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute - 1957 Reports (Box 59, Folder 419)
    United States Congress Subcommittee reports on internal security hearing involving Shigeto Tsuro, an exchange professor.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute - 1957 Reports (Box 59, Folder 420)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Address, 1959-1960 (Box 59, Folder 421)
    For 10th anniversary of Institute; copy of address and of excerpts of Grayson Kirk's address.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - East Asian Institute, 1951-1952 (Box 60, Folder 422)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - New York School of Social Work, 1950-1961 (Box 60, Folder 423)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd made 1951 contribution; other requests declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - New York School of Social Work, 1956-1961 (Box 60, Folder 0423A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - New York School of Social Work - Rockefeller Family Award, 1957-1958 (Box 60, Folder 424)
    Award to the American family "which has made the most outstanding and lasting contribution to health, education, and welfare." John D. Rockefeller 3rd accepted award on behalf of family. Comments by friends on significance of award. Tribute by D. D. Eisenhower. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Presbyterian Hospital, 1911-1961 (Box 60, Folder 425)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Presbyterian Hospital, 1911-1961 (Box 60, Folder 425A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - School of Law, 1954-1960 (Box 60, Folder 426)
    Appeal to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for major gift in 1954 declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College, 1897-1907 (Box 60, Folder 427)
    1901 contributions toward scholarship funds; 1902 John D. Rockefeller gift of $500,000 for endowment. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $200,000 toward library, 1922. Requests to serve on boards, invitations; reorganization of college. David Rockefeller gift, 1955. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, David Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College, 1922-1960 (Box 60, Folder 0427A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College, 1948-1953 (Box 60, Folder 428)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - International Institute - Paul Monroe, 1922-1933 (Box 60, Folder 429)
    International Education Board gives $100,000 towards education of foreign students at college.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Citizenship Education Project, 1954-1955 (Box 60, Folder 430)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd interested.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Junior Colleges, 1951-1959 (Box 61, Folder 431)
    Mary Clark Rockefeller contributions towards improving nurses education in junior colleges; develop two-year nursing course. Correspondents include Mary Clark Rockefeller, Arthur Jones, Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School
    Laurance S. Rockefeller's school work; gifts to O. W. Caldwell; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on Latin and grading system. David Rockefeller and the school bank; Nelson A. Rockefeller's study habits; staff at Lincoln School; Winthrop Rockefeller's grades at Loomis. Building plans; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s purchase of property for school. 1930 survey of operations. Requests from students for aid. School attended by Rodman Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, O. W. Caldwell, W. F. Russell.
    - 1941 (Box 61, Folder 0431A)
    - 1920-1940 (Box 61, Folder 0431B)
    - 1929-1942 (Box 61, Folder 0431C)
    - 1932-1959 (Box 61, Folder 431)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Horace Mann and Lincoln School, 1944-1957 (Box 61, Folder 432)
    Court struggle over continuation of school. No Rockefeller involvement. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Horace Mann and Lincoln School, 1948-1957 (Box 61, Folder 0432A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - School of Experimentation, 1932-1934 (Box 61, Folder 433)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $50,000 to support Caldwell's work at Teachers College. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, W. O. Caldwell.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - School of Experimentation - Emily Barnes Memorial Fund, 1951-1952 (Box 61, Folder 0433A)
    Pension for Anne T. Easton.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - School of Experimentation - Nelson A. Rockefeller Article, 1940 (Box 61, Folder 434)
    Article in "Link" urging Inter-American understanding.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - School of Experimentation - Cabin at Pocantico, 1923-1929 (Box 61, Folder 435)
    School built shelter on Rockefeller lands; used for six years.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School - 1939-1940 Controversy, 1939-1941 (Box 61, Folder 436)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller finances study of Lincoln School by Institute of Public Administration. Questions over future of school, possibly discontinuing it. Gulick's report. Nelson A. Rockefeller resigned from Parent Committee before controversy settled. Lincoln and Horace Mann schools merged, 1941. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Luther Gulick, Elmer Davis.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School - Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal, 1924-1928 (Box 61, Folder 437)
    Copies of Parents Committee meeting minutes. Comments on Nelson A. Rockefeller's activities. Nelson A. Rockefeller's comments on progress of program for change. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School - Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal, 1939-1941 (Box 61, Folder 438)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School - Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal, 1939-1940 (Box 62, Folder 439)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School - Nelson A. Rockefeller Resignation, 1940 (Box 62, Folder 0439A)
    Letters urging Nelson A. Rockefeller to reconsider decision to resign. Form response.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School - Report, prob. 1940's (Box 62, Folder 440)
    Report on its problems.
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Lincoln School - Master Copy of Report, 1940's (Box 62, Folder 0440A)
  - Colleges - Columbia University - Teacher's College - Summary Report - Survey Committee of the Affiliated Schools of Teacher's College, June 1930 (Box 62, Folder 0440B)
    Survey Committee of the Affiliated Schools of Teachers College. Put together to show the general history and makeup of the schools, the services provided to the students by the schools, and the impact which the schools make upon the educational world.
  - Colleges - Connecticut College, 1947-1961 (Box 63, Folder 441)